HENRY CURRAN PAPERS (APAP237) 1961-1968
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Henry Curran Papers 1961-1968
nam_apap237
1.8
Curran, Henry
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Henry Curran Papers contain materials from Curran's decade of service in the New York State Senate from 1961-1968. The collection includes committee work, sponsored legislation, correspondence, reports, and news clippings from his tenure.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Henry Curran initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in the late 1960s. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Henry Curran was born in Lock Haven, Pennsylvania in 1918 and graduated from Pace College. He served as an officer on the European front during World War II and during the Korean War. He married Rita Rothmann and together they had three sons and one daughter in Oyster Bay, Long Island.
A Republican, Curran began his political career as a deputy sheriff and was elected town clerk of Oyster Bay in 1953. Seven years later voters elected him to the New York State Senate representing the Third District, which covers part of Nassau County. During his tenure in the State Senate, he was chairman of the Joint Legislative Committee to Revise Banking Law and a member of the Joint Legislative Committee on Election Law, the committee on Matrimonial and Family Laws, the committee on Penal Institutions, as well as a member of the Education, Finance, Mental Hygiene, Roads and Public Works, Taxation, and Towns and Counties committees. Curran left the State Senate and Governor Nelson Rockefeller appointed him chair the New York State Harness Racing Commission in 1969. He held that post until 1975.
In addition to his public service, Curran was a partner in Curran, Cooney, Penny Agency, Inc., a general insurance firm in Garden City, Long Island. He also was a trustee of the Emigrant Savings Bank.
Curran died in North Shore University Hospital in Glen Cove, NY on March 13th, 1993.
Scope and Content Information
The Henry Curran Papers consist of a mixture of sponsored legislation files and news clippings from Curran's tenure in the New York State Senate (1961-1968). The former contains draft or final copies of the bill, fact sheets, and memos. The clips are predominantly about Curran, his career or banking law. The Curran Papers also include two reports from the Joint Legislative Committee to Revise Banking Law from 1967 and 1968 as well as supplementary material related to that committee's work.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Legislation, 1961-1968
Series 2 - Newspaper Clippings, 1964, 1967-1968
Series 1 and 2 are both arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Politics and Politicians; Curran, Henry; New York (State). Legislature. Senate; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committee on Education; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committee on Finance; Politicians--New York (State); New York (State). Banking law; New York (State)--Politics and government; Nassau County (N.Y.); Bills (legislative records); Clippings; Correspondence; Congressional committee reports; Legislative records
Container List
- Legislation, 1961-1968; 1; 1 cubic foot
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series consists of legislation that Curran sponsored. Most of the files include draft or final copies of the bill, fact sheets, and memos. These memos are addressed to various parties, such as other legislators. A few press releases are included as well as the Joint Committee to Revise Banking Law reports from 1967 and 1968 and related supplementary materials. This supplemental material consists largely of committee testimony.
  - Legislation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Legislative record, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Legislation, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Legislation, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Legislative record, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Legislation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Supplemental materials, Joint Legislative Committee to Revise Banking Laws, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Final Report, Joint Legislative Committee to Revise Banking Laws (1 and 2 of 3), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Final Report, Joint Legislative Committee to Revise Banking Laws (3 of 3), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Final Report, Joint Legislative Committee to Revise the Banking Law, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Clippings, 1964; 1967-1968; Undated; 2; .8 cu. ft.
  This series is composed entirely of newspaper articles likely sent to Curran or his staff from a news clipping service. Most of the clippings are related to banking law or Curran’s career. There are a few related to adoption. Please note the clippings for the year 1964 cover a variety of topics ranging from obscenity and moral issues to general news.
  - Adoption, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General newsclippings, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
  - Newsclippings, 1967 August (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newsclippings, 1967 September (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newsclippings, 1967 October (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings, 1967 November (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1967 November-1967 December (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Career, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Newsclippings, 1968 January (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings, 1968 February-1968 March (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings, 1968 March (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newsclippings, 1968 April (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Newsclippings, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)